{
    "id": "729379a5abd14db79535b61b0d1f2a80",
    "title": "Gap Fills Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "He talked as if he ………………….. everything, but he didn’t.",
            "description": "After as if and as though we use a past tense with a  present meaning to show that a comparison is unreal.",
            "answers": [
                "knows",
                "knew",
                "had known"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "d3a3fe4735714a1380c3137e04102a78"
        },
        {
            "question": "……………………….. in Germany, I got to befriend a musician.",
            "description": "The sentence can also be written as: While he was in Germany… This structure is not possible with as.",
            "answers": [
                "As",
                "While",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "64e7dc1b6d074db594645b3809b9f20a"
        },
        {
            "question": "You look ………………………….. you are about to cry.",
            "description": "We can use as if and as though to say what a situation seems like.",
            "answers": [
                "as if",
                "as though",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "5c88374db86d4219b3ed6a6687d46cdf"
        },
        {
            "question": "……………………. I was a child, I stayed with my grandparents.",
            "description": "We use when to refer to periods of life.",
            "answers": [
                "As",
                "When",
                "While"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "f8ee10f6b950407fa6442f1edc1ad676"
        },
        {
            "question": "Don’t ask me ………………………",
            "description": "To ask for something is to ask somebody to give something.",
            "answers": [
                "money",
                "for money",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "600778fafaf5496386fcb7cca0a61297"
        },
        {
            "question": "James, as well as, Janet ……………………… excited to hear the news.",
            "description": "When we connect two subjects with as well as, the verb is singular when the first subject is singular.",
            "answers": [
                "was",
                "were",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "7ffadcecee8f404fbc1c62a052ea6f1a"
        },
        {
            "question": "I answered all the questions ………………………. one.",
            "description": "But can mean except after all.",
            "answers": [
                "except",
                "but",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "24c98a53327740b182b4d15128605e54"
        },
        {
            "question": "Nobody but ………………………. would do a thing like that.",
            "description": "Object pronouns are more common after but. Subject pronouns are possible in a formal style.",
            "answers": [
                "he",
                "him",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "a7106e50c9d94d4aadff3d09391721d4"
        },
        {
            "question": "The car is too …………………….. for the garage.",
            "description": "We use wide to talk about the physical distance from one side of something to the other.",
            "answers": [
                "wide",
                "broad",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "a8b17ff6a69c44a5aedc50c07d08d2f2"
        },
        {
            "question": "You ………………………. write good English in a few months.",
            "description": "We use will be able to to talk about future ability.",
            "answers": [
                "can",
                "will be able to",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "5c8854a922c4469c80edc221bef83fb8"
        },
        {
            "question": "I wish that I …………………….. prettier.",
            "description": "In that-clauses after wish we normally use a past tense with a present or future meaning. In a formal style, were is possible instead of was in this structure.",
            "answers": [
                "was",
                "were",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "e5007e3be602422aa20d14092f1cf7cc"
        },
        {
            "question": "Don’t fight ……………………. him – he is much bigger than you.",
            "description": "After fight, quarrel, argue, struggle and play, 'with' can be used with the same meaning as against.",
            "answers": [
                "with",
                "to",
                "on"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "9d68746155c742b49a300a700c25205a"
        }
    ]
}